inventnow.org 2010-12-19

# InventNow.org - Privacy Policy

## The Information we collect

We will not collect or store any personal information about you when you visit the inventnow.org Web site unless you choose to provide that information to us. If you choose to register at the site, we will ask you for a user name, password and an email address. We do not require you to submit any information that is uniquely identifiable. This site is in compliance with COPPA rules and regulations for users under the age of 13. 

Any information you provide to us is confidential. We will only use your personal information to make this site as helpful and easy to use as possible. We will not share any information you provide us with anyone outside the inventnow.org site for any reason. 

At inventnow.org the only personally identifiable information we collect from users 12 years old and younger is a parents valid email address. And, we ONLY use this information to send these users one message to activate their inventnow.org account. 

Inventnow.org requires users 13 years and older to enter either their or their parent or guardian's valid email address in order to activate their account. 

For some of our online activities - such as polls or surveys - we may ask users to provide additional information that is not personally identifiable, such as state of residence or a visitor's favorite color. 

We do not knowingly collect names and email addresses from children under 13. We always require children under 13 to use a parent or guardians email address instead. 

Additionally, when visitors come to our site, we automatically collect some non-personally identifiable "computer" information, such as the type of computer operating system (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), the user's "IP Address", the web browser (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer) being used, and information regarding the Internet service provider. 

## Cookies

InventNow.org uses a software technology called" session cookies." A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are. 

A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site. 

## Important message about sites linked from InventNow.org

When you click on links from the InventNow.org site to another site, we will open that site in a new window. We make every effort to link to appropriate outside sites for kids. Unlike InventNow.org, these outside sites may collect personal information. Please be careful when submitting any personal information on the internet. Always ask an adult for help if you have a question. 

While InventNow.org has reviewed these other sites, we are not responsible for the content or any products or services that may be offered through these sites. 

If you come across a link that we have provided that you think should be removed. [Please Contact Us](mailto:siteabuse@inventnow.org) to let us know. 

## A Message for Kids

We want you to know the information collected from you is so you can take full advantage of all the features on our site. Inspiring Invention is a safe website you can use to learn, grow, and have fun. In return, we hope you will be respectful of all the users on this online community. As an inventnow.org member, you agree that you will not create more than one user account, that the use of an indecent screen name, profanity, language and/or images that are considered obscene and generally improper will not be tolerated. You will not use or manipulate the games, message boards or mailing areas of the inventnow.org site in inappropriate ways. 

Please read the terms and conditions for more information. 

## A Message for Parents

For the creators of Inventnow.org, learning and fun come first. Therefore, we have implemented the following measures to ensure your child's privacy: 

  * The only information Inventnow.org will collect from our site visitors is their first name, last name, date of birth, and e-mail address. (Changes made)
  * We communicate directly with the players or their parents, as specified by COPPA, and do not share information with anyone. No third parties will receive any of your child's personal information.
  * While some of our games and activities are on external servers, we carefully select and monitor our participating sites with the children in mind. You will be notified when you leave our site and connect to another site. We can not control the content on other sites, we do review all the sites that we provide links to and make every effort to ensure the content is appropriate. 
  * All site content on invnetnow.org is appropriate for young children. In selecting the content of our site, we did our best to avoid links to sites with advertisements.
  * We discourage children from sharing personal information when they interact with other players on the site.
  * All interaction on the site is monitored to foster a positive and appropriate online experience for all users.
  * Our site uses cookies (a type of technology that stores user's preferences) for the advantage of the children who play the games online. Personal information irrelevant to the game is not stored in the process.

If you have any specific questions about the inventnow.org site or privacy policy, please contact us.(email link to For more about the Ad Council's mission, please visit [www.adcouncil.org](http://www.adcouncil.org/), for information about The National Inventors Hall of Fame Foundation (NIHFF), please visit http://www.invent.org/ and for more info on the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO), please visit [www.uspto.gov](http://www.uspto.gov/).
